<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on cruisemaniac.com</title><link>https://cruisemaniac.com/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on cruisemaniac.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cruisemaniac.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Remote - Part 1 of n...</title><link>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/how-to-remote-part-1-of-n.../</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/how-to-remote-part-1-of-n.../</guid><description>I just scribbled this down since I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked multiple times on how to be efficient when working from home. Here&amp;rsquo;s some tips that will hopefully help you:
Have a separate place to work. Have a separate place to sleep / eat / relax. Do not mix them up. Everyone makes the mistake of working from their beds. Stop that!
Have specific times to work. Dont go into this never-ending spree of working because you have a stable internet connection and uninterrupted power.</description></item><item><title>Go Remote or Wind up!</title><link>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/go-remote-or-wind-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/go-remote-or-wind-up/</guid><description>The whole #covid19 pandemic is an amazing opportunity to gear up for the next level.
For every single organization looking to hire for the best employees out there, here&amp;rsquo;s just 2 words: Go Remote!
Treat this international situation as an opportunity to hire remotely. And Here&amp;rsquo;s why: A person who says he / she will work remote has already ticked off a lot of boxes -
They&amp;rsquo;re self motivated They learn on their own They can work with a broad requirement and dig around to get work done.</description></item><item><title>Here's to 2013 and a great 2014</title><link>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/heres-to-2013-and-a-great-2014/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cruisemaniac.com/post/heres-to-2013-and-a-great-2014/</guid><description>2013 was an amazing year in many respects! Worked on more things than before - learnt a ton of new things&amp;hellip;
Infrastructure management - I got my hands dirty with something i&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered what it was. Knowing how to organize your infrastructure, sizing, planning, creating new machines, the cloud and yes, Amazon EC2 as well!
Got better at automating software delivery - helped improve processes at work! A tiny little tool that I wrote has run with 0 downtime for the last year!</description></item></channel></rss>